Francisco Alvarado

Full Stack Developer

Houston, TX | 832-504-5844 | francisco.alvarado217@yahoo.com

LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

SUMMARY

For the past 4+ years, I have been honing my skills as a welder. This experience has instilled in me a strong work ethic, attention to detail, and a commitment to safety qualities that are equally valuable in the field of software development. During my tenure as a welder, I discovered a passion for coding and software development in my spare time. I have been self-studying programming languages such as JavaScript, HTML/CSS and enrolled in a Full Stack Software Engineering bootcamp

SKILLS

FRONT END: HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React.js, Tailwind CSS

BACK END: Node.js, Express.js, RESTful API's **DATABASES:** PostgreSQL, SQL, MongoDB **OTHER:** Git, GitHub, VSCode, DBeaver

PROJECTS

PERSONAL PORTFOLIO WEBSITE [demo | GitHub]

- Created a responsive and visually appealing portfolio website showcasing projects, skills, and achievements
- Implemented interactive features using JavaScript

CAR RENTAL SITE [demo | GitHub]

- Created an aesthetically refined frontend car rental website with React and CSS
- Utilized flex, grid, custom CSS, media queries, JSX, made responsive, React hooks.

FLASHCARD APP [GitHub]

- Built an application that allows users to create, study, and edit flashcards for educational purposes.
- Utilized React hooks to build SPA using single-purpose components and read-only props.
- Developed full stack app using NPM, JSX, and React.

DECODER RING [demo | GitHub]

- Built a message decoder that allows users to encode or decode secret messages using 3 different cipher algorithms
- Utilized HTML, CSS, JavaScript, functions, if/else statements

THINKFULBNB [demo | GitHub]

- Built a rental website that allows users to rent out their homes with HTML and CSS
- Utilized HTML, CSS, is mobile-first responsive

EXPERIENCE

FULLSTACK SOFTWARE ENGINEERING BOOTCAMP STUDENT JUNE 2023 - CURRENT

Thinkful | Houston, Tx

- Enrolled in a rigorous Full Stack SOftware Engineering Bootcamp, gaining hands on experience in both front-end and back-end development
- Acquired proficiency in modern web development tools and frameworks, including HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ReactJS, NodeJS, ExpressJs
- Developed and deployed various web applications, emphasizing best practices in coding standards, scalability, and user experience

SELF-TAUGHT LEARNING AUG 2022 - CURRENT

Houston, Tx

- Engaged in independent study and self taught learning in software development
- Demonstrated commitment to continuous learning by staying up-to-date with industry trends and exploring emerging technologies

EDUCATION

THINKFUL | thinkful.com JUN 2023 - EXPECTED MAR 2024

Bootcamp | Software Engineering Immersion

- Full stack software engineering development program.
- Designed mobile-first full stack applications from conception to deployment, learning industry best practices.

SAN JACINTO COLLEGE JAN 2022 - DEC 2022

College | Houston, Texas

• One year completion in Comp Science courses.

CHANNELVIEW HIGH SCHOOL AUG 2015 - MAY 2018

Diploma - High School | Channelview, Texas

• Completed all fields of education to obtain a High School diploma in 3 years.